# Optical-Pumping

## Abstract
Optical pumping apparatus will be used to attain a measurement of the Landé g factor of Caesium and the local magnetic flux density of the Earth. The experiment also seeks to attain observations for changes in Rabi oscillations through a series of RF frequencies. Here we added an extra external magnetic field and varied the additional flux density, observing what effect this has on the resonance point of the Caesium allows the extraction of the desired measurements.The process resulted in a value of 0.262±0.003 for Caesium’s Landé g factor which compares well with the accepted theoretical value. The flux density extracted from the data fit is(47.68±0.01) μT which corresponds withthe local magnetic flux density within the laboratory at the time of the experiment, this value is within the expected range of the fluctuation of the earth’s magnetic field at the co-ordinates and elevation of the working environment.

## Acknowledgements

This research is a collaboration between myself and N. Mak without whom the experiment would not have been effectively completed  to as high a level of accuracy nor within reasonable time restraints. With aid from those at the MPhys Physics Laboratory for the use of equipment as well as the staff that ensure all of the equipment is maintained and functional throughout the process of the experiment.

 We gratefully acknowledge the support of Dr. I. Vivarelli who was the laboratory supervisor for this experiment providing insight and guidance throughout the experimental procedure.s